Aaron Lademann

573.356.0456 | aaron.lademann@gmail.com

My objective is to provide innovative business solutions for a progressive company seeking creativity and leadership. I have more than eight years of experience - combining an eclectic range of design, development, marketing and analytical skills with proven leadership abilities that drive teams to have fun producing profitable results.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Creative Director

St. Louis, MO | 09.2008 - Present

Fpweb.net LC | *The World Leader in SharePoint Hosting Services*

Manage the Web Services and Marketing departments by fostering a team environment that cultivates innovation and empowers individuals to take creative chances without fear of failure. Demonstrate servant leadership by providing hands-on assistance in all phases of project management and concept development.

Responsibilities

- Plan, create and adhere to two department budgets simultaneously
- Provide long-term department goals based on relevant KPI and team velocity
- Optimize performance of Web and Marketing teams by providing consistent rewards & recognition
- Provide creative direction to ensure brand consistency across all Web, Marketing and Sales initiatives
- Research and monitor Web analytics and usability testing increase the quality and quantity of sales leads
- Oversee the daily management of thousands of pages of online content for internal and external customers
- Provide strategic direction for the company as a member of the Board of Directors

Key Accomplishments

- Reinvented the Fpweb.net brand with a total identity and Web site transformation
- Increased online organic sales conversions by over 400%
- Improved Fpweb.net visitor traffic by over 63%
- Retained all but one team member through the 2009 recession
- Oversaw department growth of over 150% three consecutive years

Web UI/UX Developer & Designer

St. Louis, MO | 04.2008 - 09.2008

Fpweb.net LC | *The World Leader in SharePoint Hosting Services*

Responsibilities

- Lead the Web interface design efforts for Fpweb.net, the flagship Web property of Fpweb.net LC
- Manage source control and drive quality control for a 300+ page dynamic ASP Web site

Key Accomplishments

- Awarded the company's highest honor in my third month of employment
- Promoted to department head after only five months ahead of individuals with longer tenures

Web Specialist & Art Director

St. Louis, MO | 04.2007 - 07.2008

Sisters of Mercy Health System | Ninth largest Catholic health system in the United States

Responsibilities

- Plan, develop and manage all Web interaction and communication within the corporation
- Utilize a Stellent™ content management system to organize four internal intranet Web sites
- Provide guidance to executives in identifying and implementing Web solutions in support of business needs
- Provide creative direction to enhance public-facing marketing efforts and brand consistency

Key Accomplishments

- Developed a physician intranet site to facilitate interaction and communication between thousands of Mercy doctors, helping to increase adaptation of a new five-billion dollar EHR system.
- Designed a new corporate branding strategy to align the visual treatments of all logos and symbols used throughout numerous umbrella corporations within the health system.

Web Developer

Belleville, IL | 09.2006 - 05.2007

MonsterCommerce | A home-grown St. Louis internet startup acquired by Network Solutions in 2007

Responsibilities

- Design, develop and implement effective Web interfaces using css/html
- Determine and manage project time lines, and handle a workload of up to ten clients at once
- Perform user requirements gathering, prototyping, interface & graphic design, and SEO/PPC optimization
- Nominated for designer of the month three times, and won the award during my second month on the team

Design Intern

Belleville, IL | 05.2006 - 09.2006

MonsterCommerce | A home-grown St. Louis internet startup acquired by Network Solutions in 2007

Responsibilities

- Work with a team of interns from various backgrounds to plan, develop & launch a successful online venture
- Personally responsible for brand development, interface design, user studies and usability enhancements
- Develop a twenty-five page guide to accompany our business plan for prospective VC investors

Graphic Designer & Production Supervisor

Columbia, MO | 05.2002 - 05.2006

Signs Now, Inc. | A one-stop advertising & marketing shop for small-businesses

Responsibilities

- Turn client visions into effective brand identity & marketing tools through various traditional media
- Train and supervise three production associates to ensure quality output on all finished media
- Plan and execute large-scale on-site installation projects, keeping them within scope and budget. Operate and maintain small and large format ink jet/heat transfer printing and lamination equipment. Implement and provide quality-assurance for all pre-press color standards and equipment calibration methods

EDUCATION

Computer Information Systems

Columbia, MO | 08.2003 - 12.2006

Columbia College | Private College accredited by The Higher Learning Commission

- Graduated Cum Laude with a 3.64 GPA, Bachelor of Science in CIS with a Minor in Business Administration
- Specialization/Emphasis in the studies of Human-Computer-Interaction (HCI) & Psychology
- Achieved dean's list recognition five time

Computer Graphics Technology

West Lafayette, IN | 08.2000 - 08.2002

Purdue University | One of the most prestigious Computer Graphics programs in the World

- Studied 3D animation, textures, lighting methods and advanced typography

KNOWLEDGE & SKILLS

Management & Communication

- Microsoft Office Outlook, Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Visio, Access { Expert Knowledge }
- Project management using MS Exchange tools for shared tasks, workflows and calendars { Expert Knowledge }
- Excellent written and verbal communication skills, relentless work-ethic
- Passionate about servant-leadership & helping my team grow as people and professionals
- Experienced public speaker and presenter

Web Application Development & Interface Design

- Microsoft Visual Studio 2008, Adobe Dreamweaver { Expert Knowledge }
- Microsoft Team Foundation Server & Git Source Control { Expert Knowledge }
- jQuery, Traditional JavaScript, Ajax, XML, (x)HTML, ASP, ASP.NET, SQL, CSS { Expert Knowledge }
- Human-computer interaction (UI/UX) analysis { Expert Knowledge }
- Wireframe & Paper prototype development using Balsamiq { Expert Knowledge }
- Requirements gathering, Business-process engineering, Workflow design { Expert Knowledge }
- Oracle Stellent Site Studio CMS, WebDav Content Publishing
- Agile development methodology

Graphic Design & Creative Direction

- Brand creation, enhancement & management { Expert Knowledge }
- Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign) { Expert Knowledge }
- Microsoft Office template production for brand letterhead & presentations { Expert Knowledge }
- Art Direction, Media Production, Advanced typography & layout optimization
- Market Research & Advertising Concept Development